[Autogenerated] If you ever deploy the infrastructure manually,
you know the feeling.
You click a few buttons and your Kubernetis clusters start running.
But later on, if you try to repeat the same deployment,
you missed a couple of things here and there.
Infrastructure as a code exists exactly to prevent that.
Let's How we can use the Terraform to deploy the clusters
and resources into the Google Cloud.
For this,
I assume that you already have VS Code installed and in
that you have already added the Terraform.
If you're not aware of it, you simply go down to the Google.
And it is straightforward to install the VS Code and similarly it
is straightforward to install the Terraform.
Lastly,
I also assume that you have a Google SDK is also
installed on your local machine.
Now I'm using the MacBook,
but this exercise can be easily done on the Windows machine as well.
Now in the Terraform, we should have a one file, main.tf.
This is to initialize the Terraform configure.
I start defining by the Google provider.
Then I'm enabling the required APIs,
and we are creating the VPC network and subnet through this specific code.
Now on similar lines,
I have the variables.tf that contains a couple of
variables where I have given the name, the project ID,
region, and our network name and our subnetwork name as a variable,
and we have Outputs.tf where we have defined the output,
network name, subnetwork self-link,
and lastly we have terraform.tf wars where I'm providing the project
ID where I'm going to exactly create all of these.
It's time to go and run that.
So first thing which we need to do is Google Cloud authentication.
So here in the terminal,
I'm typing GCloud Auth application default login and say E.
This will redirect, and I'll do the Google authentication.
Now, once the authentication has been done, I'm going to run Terraform in it.
That will initialize.
Then I'm going to run a Terraform plan that will give me the exact plan.
What you're going to create.
And then finally I'm going to say Terraform apply.
Now this is the point where it goes and actually start
deploying our resources into the.
Google Cloud.
Now you can see that it has successfully created our resources.
Now I go down to my Google Cloud, go down to my specific project that is HPC1,
and inside that, if I go down to my VPC there,
so you can see that I got it demo VPC1, and if I go inside the demo VPC 1,
I should be able to see the subnet as well.
That is demo subnet 1.
So that's how our Terraform has created the resource into the Google Cloud.
On similar lines, we can also use the CFT.
CFT stands for Google Cloud Foundation Toolit.
They are the already approved templates from the Google
which you can use to create your infrastruc.
as a code.
For example, in this, I'm using the CFT network module from the CFT,
which is an approved module for creating the network resources.
So instead of writing your own code,
you can use the pre-built templates from the Google CFT and you
can use that for creating your resources.